<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>opinion on Ruben Krueger</title>
    <link>/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in opinion on Ruben Krueger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:19:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Transition</title>
      <link>/posts/a-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-transition/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I left the world of software engineering and startups to enter academic clinical research. Specifically, I work now as a Data Analyst at the Brain Stimulation Lab at Stanford. The lab studies the use of neuromodulation (i.e., non-invasive methods of altering brain activity) in psychiatric diseases like depression and OCD.Thus, instead of building a website, I work on data pipelines and the analysis of neuroimaging data (e.g., MRI and EEG).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Runner&#39;s Guide to Calf Strains</title>
      <link>/posts/a-runners-guide-to-calf-strains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-runners-guide-to-calf-strains/</guid>
      <description>If you’re a true runner like me, you will run even if it hurts. You will run even if you know you probably shouldn’t, and you will eventually run until you’re injured — that point when a single step will cause pain or discomfort in your knees, hips, or foot. Whether this compulsion to run stems from the competitive drive to train for a race, the desperate search for the runner’s high, or a psychological hole that only running can fill, our love of running will eventually hurt us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Home</title>
      <link>/posts/coming-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coming-home/</guid>
      <description>At night, I left my house and looked up. The stars were white pinpoint holes in the dark sky, distant beyond my comprehension.
I looked down. Through some hedges, I saw the busy street I live next to. Each car zoomed past, spewing noxious fumes as the drivers rushed to get home. Like them, I had driven through traffic to an office, typed on a computer, and driven through traffic back home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
