<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ruben Krueger</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ruben Krueger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Empty Promises</title>
      <link>/posts/empty-promises/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 17:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/empty-promises/</guid>
      <description>If you drive on Highway 101 in the Bay Area, you will notice something curious while navigating traffic: most billboard signs advertise companies you’ve never heard of unless you are in “tech.” These companies range in size from billion-dollar behemoths to fledgling startups, but they share one thing in common: they are all, more or less, software companies.
This observation is the manifestation of a well-known fact: there is a glut of software companies in Silicon Valley — “software is eating the world,” as Marc Andressen famously said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Open Problem</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-important-open-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 18:35:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-most-important-open-problem/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked which open problem in science I think is the most important.1 I always respond, “does P = NP?”2
A mathematically-inclined (and perhaps jocular) reader at this point will think “yes, when N=1.&amp;quot; A reader with a background in computer science (but is not, say, a theoretical computer science professor) will gaze in the foreground, trying to remember the contours of this problem from their algorithms class. A reader who is struggling to understand the footnotes will also probably not understand how the prose got to this point, along with the reader who was skimming these words (and is daydreaming by now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Worst Argument to Descend Down</title>
      <link>/posts/the-worst-argument-to-descend-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-worst-argument-to-descend-down/</guid>
      <description>The argument In discussions I have participated in, I have noticed that people make slippery-slope arguments when they have no other good arguments to make. To provide an example, let’s look at two people who are debating methods of protecting local farmland from floods.
Person A: “We must build a dam on the river, or else our crops will be destroyed again and again.”
Person B: “We cannot build the dam, because this a slippery-slope until we build dams on all of our rivers and creeks, and this would be horrible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A paradox</title>
      <link>/posts/a-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-paradox/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, a man, Paul the Publican, opens a pub. To get customers, he puts up a large sign in front of his establishment: “Cheaper than all bars in Oldtown.” For a few years, it worked: his bar is packed most nights. In fact, his prices are so cheap that all of the other bars in Newton close for a lack of business.
However, Paul gets tired of Oldtown and moves the pub to the nearby Newtown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Home</title>
      <link>/posts/coming-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coming-home/</guid>
      <description>At night, I left my house and looked up. The stars were white pinpoint holes in the dark sky, distant beyond my comprehension.
I looked down. Through some hedges, I saw the busy street I live next to. Each car zoomed past, spewing noxious fumes as the drivers rushed to get home. Like them, I had driven through traffic to an office, typed on a computer, and driven through traffic back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running</title>
      <link>/posts/on-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-running/</guid>
      <description>I love to run. It’s part of who I am. It’s perhaps the most important thing in life to me — without it, I cannot be happy. And this is clear to those that know me; one of my friends once said that running was my “personality.”
Running through streets and trails makes me feel in touch with the outdoors. I generally do not listen to music when I run; I enjoy disconnecting from electronics (save for my watch) and zoning out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cheese Grater</title>
      <link>/posts/the-cheese-grater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-cheese-grater/</guid>
      <description>The medical school application process is broken. In no way is this better exemplified than the secondary application process; or, as I like to think of it, the “cheese grater.”
Applying to medical school is done in multiple stages. The first stage is the primary application, which consists of sending essays (e.g., “why medicine?”), transcripts, and other demographic information to your list of chosen medical schools. After some bureaucratic wrangling by the AAMC — the “non-profit” behind this mess — medical schools send the secondary application to students who have sent their primary application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing</title>
      <link>/posts/on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I.
Writing is a terrible profession and an even worse hobby. Most writers are underpaid, overworked, and miserable. (I, on the other hand, am overpaid, underworked, and still miserable). But when you write for “fun,” as I do, you do not have the benefit of editors, deadlines, or a dedicated audience. (Should I have used “nor” in this preceding sentence? Who knows!)
I suppose I should explain why I hate writing, even though I offer it as a “passion” of mine when someone asks to describe myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suicide, the disease</title>
      <link>/posts/suicide-the-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/suicide-the-disease/</guid>
      <description>“I believe that suicide is a natural history, a disease process,” Donald Antrim writes in One Friday in April, his recently-published book on his struggles with suicide and depression. Suicide is, in Donald’s words, “not an act or a choice, a decision or a wish.” This, in fact, is the central interrogation of the book: the question of free will for the suicidal man.
The trouble, of course, is that suicide is generally defined as willful self-killing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 6th: A Story Mistold</title>
      <link>/posts/a-story-mistold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-story-mistold/</guid>
      <description>Humans understand the world through stories. These may be ones of heroism, failure, or both; regardless, it is not sober facts that inspire action in us, but narratives. The events of January 6th, 2021 show a disturbing tale believed by some Americans.
In a “Save America” rally that day, Trump told his supporters to “fight like hell” to, well, save their country. This was the story that thousands of right-wing militia men, real estate agents, and veterans told themselves: the election was stolen, Trump is our president, and we must return him to power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Guide to Webscraping With Python</title>
      <link>/posts/a-simple-guide-to-webscraping-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-simple-guide-to-webscraping-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Webscraping is the process of pulling data from websites, typically using a script. Webscraping is a wonderful thing: like many other automations, you can save hours (or more) of work. I&amp;rsquo;ve found this skill to be incredible useful, as I&amp;rsquo;ve applied it to many different projects. In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to write a Python script that creates a CSV file of data from a fake online bookstore. This tutorial assumes that you understand the basics of Python (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Uncomfortable Truth</title>
      <link>/posts/an-uncomfortable-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 17:05:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-uncomfortable-truth/</guid>
      <description>There are many uncomfortable truths in our callous society. I would like to impart just one to you today: each day, people in our society die because they cannot afford prescription drugs. These deaths are preventable and they are the consequences of decisions made by pharmaceutical executives, lawmakers, and our political system (this is an argument which I will make in a future post).
Before we explore this uncomfortable truth, I would like to dispel some myths about drug prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Remote Work Explained with Graphs</title>
      <link>/posts/the-failure-of-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:35:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-failure-of-remote-work/</guid>
      <description>When you are able to reach anyone in your remote organization instantly through Slack or email, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t barriers across teams and locations disappear? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t information sharing increase and ideas be generated more easily? One would think so — is this not a benefit of working in a virtual environment?
Whether or not knowledge workers will return back to the office is hotly debated right now. Major companies like Apple and Google have delayed their plans to return back to office, and regardless of the ultimate outcome, our relationship to where we work has fundamentally been changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Darkest Net</title>
      <link>/posts/the-darkest-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-darkest-net/</guid>
      <description>One does not have to spend long on the internet to see vile, offensive, or otherwise malicious content. The classic example is the comments section of a political YouTube video, where interlocuters compare each other to historical tyrants. In Jamie Bartlett&amp;rsquo;s book The Dark Net, the journalist explores the Dark Net, which he defines as &amp;ldquo;internet underworlds set apart yet connected to the internet we inhabit, worlds of freedom and anonymity&amp;hellip; often uncensored unregulated and outside societys norms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Made This</title>
      <link>/posts/how-i-made-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 07:00:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-i-made-this/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: James Harrison / Unsplash
There are no shortage of front-end frameworks, no-code website builders, and website templates available. Each has their strengths and weaknesses, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used almost all of them: Wix, Squarespace, React, Vue, Bootstrap, to name a few. On my previous personal websites, I would use a template like this and customize it.
However, this approach does not lend itself to making a blog, where content needs to be served dynamically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux News</title>
      <link>/posts/faux-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faux-news/</guid>
      <description>Lies There are unknown lies; there are known lies; and there are known lies which lead to the deaths of countless people. From the inception of the pandemic, public health officials have fought against the biological danger of COVID-19 as much as the lies and deception created about COVID-19.
I was reminded of this reality when I was sitting in the examining room of a Bay Area hospital, where I was shadowing a physician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Welcome to my personal website / blog. While I am not the not best writer nor do I have any insights worth sharing, that has not stopped me!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
