<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Ruben Krueger</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Ruben Krueger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 17:23:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Unfortunate Experiment</title>
      <link>/posts/an-unfortunate-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 17:23:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-unfortunate-experiment/</guid>
      <description>If you or a loved one is having thoughts of self-harm, there is help. You can call the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 800-273-8255
To write these words is to challenge a belief I hold close to my soul: that language can express the full depth of the Human experience, and in particular, my own as I suffer the withdrawal symptoms of sertraline, a medication to which I became dependent on to soften the torments of my never-ending anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Remote Work Explained with Graphs</title>
      <link>/posts/the-failure-of-remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 18:35:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-failure-of-remote-work/</guid>
      <description>When you are able to reach anyone in your remote organization instantly through Slack or email, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t barriers across teams and locations disappear? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t information sharing increase and ideas be generated more easily? One would think so — is this not a benefit of working in a virtual environment?
Whether or not knowledge workers will return back to the office is hotly debated right now. Major companies like Apple and Google have delayed their plans to return back to office, and regardless of the ultimate outcome, our relationship to where we work has fundamentally been changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Darkest Net</title>
      <link>/posts/the-darkest-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-darkest-net/</guid>
      <description>One does not have to spend long on the internet to see vile, offensive, or otherwise malicious content. The classic example is the comments section of a political YouTube video, where interlocuters compare each other to historical tyrants. In Jamie Bartlett&amp;rsquo;s book The Dark Net, the journalist explores the Dark Net, which he defines as &amp;ldquo;internet underworlds set apart yet connected to the internet we inhabit, worlds of freedom and anonymity&amp;hellip; often uncensored unregulated and outside societys norms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Made This</title>
      <link>/posts/how-i-made-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 07:00:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-i-made-this/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: James Harrison / Unsplash
There are no shortage of front-end frameworks, no-code website builders, and website templates available. Each has their strengths and weaknesses, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used almost all of them: Wix, Squarespace, React, Vue, Bootstrap, to name a few. On my previous personal websites, I would use a template like this and customize it.
However, this approach does not lend itself to making a blog, where content needs to be served dynamically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux News</title>
      <link>/posts/faux-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faux-news/</guid>
      <description>Lies There are unknown lies; there are known lies; and there are known lies which lead to the deaths of countless people. From the inception of the pandemic, public health officials have fought against the biological danger of COVID-19 as much as the lies and deception created about COVID-19.
I was reminded of this reality when I was sitting in the examining room of a Bay Area hospital, where I was shadowing a physician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Welcome to my personal website / blog. While I am not the not best writer nor do I have any insights worth sharing, that has not stopped me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/pages/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/contact/</guid>
      <description>Fill out the form below to get in touch with me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/pages/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description>VaxMyFam.org With a group of volunteers, I helped create a website to assist non-English speakers in seven US counties in receiving vaccine information and FAQs accurately and efficiently.
Featured in: Stanford Daily
CryptoUpdater An app to view cryptocurrency data. Published on the Google Play Store.
Source code</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
