<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome on Ruben Krueger</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome on Ruben Krueger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 11:36:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Tic Tac Toe in Python</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-make-tic-tac-toe-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 11:36:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-make-tic-tac-toe-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Getting Started This tutorial assumes a basic understanding of programming (e.g., variables, functions, loops).
Mac MacOS already ships with Python 2.7.
https://www.python.org/downloads/
Windows Linux If you&amp;rsquo;re on Linux, you most likely have Python already installed. Besides, if you&amp;rsquo;re on Linux, you probably already know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing.
Subproblems When
Conclusion Extensions  Our game assumes the player&amp;rsquo;s input is correctly formatted (two valid indices separated by a comma). Can you write a program Our board is printed  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Darkest Net</title>
      <link>/posts/the-darkest-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-darkest-net/</guid>
      <description>One does not have to spend long on the internet to see vile, offensive, or otherwise malicious content. The classic example is the comments section of a political YouTube video, where interlocuters compare each other to historical tyrants. In Jamie Bartlett&amp;rsquo;s book The Dark Net, the journalist explores the Dark Net, which he defines as &amp;ldquo;internet underworlds set apart yet connected to the internet we inhabit, worlds of freedom and anonymity&amp;hellip; often uncensored unregulated and outside societys norms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Made This</title>
      <link>/posts/how-i-made-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 07:00:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-i-made-this/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: James Harrison / Unsplash
There are no shortage of front-end frameworks, no-code website builders, and website templates available. Each has their strengths and weaknesses, and I&amp;rsquo;ve used almost all of them: Wix, Squarespace, React, Vue, Bootstrap, to name a few. On my previous personal websites, I would use a template like this and customize it.
However, this approach does not lend itself to making a blog, where content needs to be served dynamically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faux News</title>
      <link>/posts/faux-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faux-news/</guid>
      <description>Lies There are unknown lies; there are known lies; and there are known lies which lead to the deaths of countless people. From the inception of the pandemic, public health officials have fought against the biological danger of COVID-19 as much as the lies and deception created about COVID-19.
I was reminded of this reality when I was sitting in the examining room of a Bay Area hospital, where I was shadowing a physician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 08:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello! Welcome to my personal website / blog. While I am not the not best writer nor do I have any insights worth sharing, that has not stopped me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/pages/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/contact/</guid>
      <description>Fill out the form below to get in touch with me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/pages/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/projects/</guid>
      <description>VaxMyFam.org With a group of volunteers, I helped create a website to assist non-English speakers in seven US counties in receiving vaccine information and FAQs accurately and efficiently.
Featured in: Stanford Daily
CryptoUpdater An app to view cryptocurrency data. Published on the Google Play Store.
Source code</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
