<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>essay on Ruben Krueger</title>
    <link>/category/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in essay on Ruben Krueger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 18:35:53 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/category/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Open Problem</title>
      <link>/posts/the-most-important-open-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 18:35:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-most-important-open-problem/</guid>
      <description>I often get asked which open problem in science I think is the most important.1 I always respond, “does P = NP?”2
A mathematically-inclined (and perhaps jocular) reader at this point will think “yes, when N=1.&amp;quot; A reader with a background in computer science (but is not, say, a theoretical computer science professor) will gaze in the foreground, trying to remember the contours of this problem from their algorithms class. A reader who is struggling to understand the footnotes will also probably not understand how the prose got to this point, along with the reader who was skimming these words (and is daydreaming by now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Worst Argument to Descend Down</title>
      <link>/posts/the-worst-argument-to-descend-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 11:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-worst-argument-to-descend-down/</guid>
      <description>The argument In discussions I have participated in, I have noticed that people make slippery-slope arguments when they have no other good arguments to make. To provide an example, let’s look at two people who are debating methods of protecting local farmland from floods.
Person A: “We must build a dam on the river, or else our crops will be destroyed again and again.”
Person B: “We cannot build the dam, because this a slippery-slope until we build dams on all of our rivers and creeks, and this would be horrible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A paradox</title>
      <link>/posts/a-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 08:40:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-paradox/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, a man, Paul the Publican, opens a pub. To get customers, he puts up a large sign in front of his establishment: “Cheaper than all bars in Oldtown.” For a few years, it worked: his bar is packed most nights. In fact, his prices are so cheap that all of the other bars in Newton close for a lack of business.
However, Paul gets tired of Oldtown and moves the pub to the nearby Newtown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Home</title>
      <link>/posts/coming-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:09:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/coming-home/</guid>
      <description>At night, I left my house and looked up. The stars were white pinpoint holes in the dark sky, distant beyond my comprehension.
I looked down. Through some hedges, I saw the busy street I live next to. Each car zoomed past, spewing noxious fumes as the drivers rushed to get home. Like them, I had driven through traffic to an office, typed on a computer, and driven through traffic back home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
